TIAN XIE (UMID: 22078225)

RESUME

Proposed Program: Computer Science Engineering | Tele: 734-882-9448 | Email: tianxie@umich.edu |

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/txie-cc | Github: https://github.com/tianxie1995

SUMMARY

Accumulated advanced skills and knowledge about GIS, Database, web application development, and data analysis, with strong problem-solving ability. Conducted advanced GIS analysis, successfully developed several web applications, actively contributed on research papers, committed to learning merging technology, and believing in changing the world with technologies. Continuously participated in collaborative work, proficient in communication with others.

EDUCATION

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor

Ann Arbor, MI

Master in Urban and Regional Planning/Urban Informatics Certificate

Expected 05.2019

GPA: 3.8/4.0

Shenzhen University

Shenzhen, China

Bachelor of Engineering -Transportation Engineering

07.2017

GPA: 3.3/4.0 Ranking: Top 1/53

EXPERIENCE

Detroit Downtown Partnership (Information Intern)

Detroit, 06.2018-

- Re-organized the organization's GIS data in ArcGIS REST server, developed a Google Geocoding API based, customized geocoder for the organization, and managed the GIS database for the DDP
- Developed and tested several web map applications as the media to share information to the businesses using JavaScript, HTML and CSS, designed and tested the open data portal pages for the organization
- Help other department in the organization solve data analysis related problems using python

University of Michigan (Research Assistant)

Ann Arbor, 10.2017-10.2018

An Alternative to Slow Transit, Drunk Driving, and Walking in the Rain: An Exploratory Study of Ride-sourcing Trip Patterns and Mode Choice

• To understand why travelers choose ride-sourcing over other travel models, utilized a voluntary survey, available online via a responsive survey tool suitable for mobile phones or desktop computers. Analyzed survey result, geocoded with Google and Nominatim geocoding API, mapped result with ArcGIS. Wrote paper about the findings.

MBTA (Short-term Intern)

Boston, 02.2018-03.2018

• To get better insight about transit line performance, help MBTA analyze GTFS and trajectory data using Data analysis tools in Python and excel.

Peking University Shenzhen Graduate School (Research Assistant)

Shenzhen, China, 08.2016 - 09.2016

Help Research team conduct analysis on transit system and its relationship with housing price

2016 China Undergraduate Mathematical Contest (the second prize)

Shenzhen, China, 10.2016

Effects of Opening the Community on Surrounding Roads

• Choosing one community in Changsha as the research object and conducting quantitative analysis on the traffic impaction of open policy based on established models and public traffic data

SKILLS

Programing Language: Python, SQL, PHP, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, C/C++, bash

Software: ArcGIS, QGIS, PostGIS, AutoCAD, Jupyter Notebook, Tableau, Matlab, R, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, AWS, Microsoft Azure, MS Office Suite, Adobe InDesign and illustrator

System: Linux, Macintosh OS X, Windows